《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我召集韦恩集团董事会开过会
I had a meeting with the board of Wayne Enterprises
跟他们说我在调查他们
to tell them I was investigating them,
于是他们就找了个我们会信任的人监视我们
so they sent someone we'd trust to spy on us.
阿尔弗雷德被人捅了
Alfred was stabbed.
是他的老战友
It was a friend of his from the army.
他想找什么
What was he looking for?
我的几份文件不见了
Some of my files were missing.
我可以查出谁雇的他
I could find out who hired him.
他是一切的关键
He's the key to everything.
我有个计划
I have a plan.
我保证
I promise you,
我能把我们中一部分人  活着弄出去
I will get some of us out of here alive.
你是谁
Who are you?
弗兰西斯・杜马赫医生
Dr. Francis Dulmacher.
地下室的人信任我
The people in the basement trust me.
让我管事
Put me in charge,
我向你保证  我能提供可靠的健康产品
and I promise you a dependable flow of healthy product.
要是我失败了呢
And if I fail?
失败者一样有用
Oh, those who fail me still have their uses.
他们要干什么
What are they doing?
对不起了  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
你在单子上
You're on the list.
哥谭市警局半数警察都有个科波特
Half the cops in the GCPD have a Cobblepot,
洛布有他们所有人的把柄
and Loeb has the goods on all of them.
这就是洛布的专长
That is what Loeb does.
那到此为止了
Well, it ends now.
你要怎么样
What do you want?
警察工会主席大选在即
With the coming election for president of the policemen's union,
我首推戈登警探
there's no man I'd rather support.
哥谭市警局迎来了新的一天
It's a new day in the GCPD.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
-卡瓦诺女士气色不错啊  -谢谢
- Hmm, looking good, Ms. Cavanaugh. - Thank you.
-肿消了吗  -还好
- How's that swelling? - Fine.
要是还要冰袋  我去跟丹妮丝说声
If you need more ice packs, I'll let Denise know.
道格拉斯先生  我知道你不满意你房间的风景
Mr. Douglas, I know you don't like your view,
等康复套房空了
and as soon as a recovery suite is open,
我立马把你转过去
I'm going to move you.
翻译：艾瑞卡   木浅薰   charcie   Reginamoon   DustD   Silence
翻译：爵士年代蓬蓬裙   草草         特效：宝宝
时间轴：Kallen   凭陵新月   想念Gallifrey的Wholock
后期：饿得慌          校对&总监：草草
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
你在外面
You're outside.
你没看错
You're observant.
我是医生的新助手
I'm the new assistant for the doctor.
我是菲什
I'm Fish.
怎么称呼你
And you are?
你在里面想怎么溜达都行
Inside you're free to roam,
那是杜马赫医生的特权
that's Dr. Dulmacher's prerogative,
但一旦你踏入外面
but once you step outside,
你就进入我的地盘了
you're in my world.
把那些有胆想逃的可怜虫
I'm the man who catches the poor souls
抓回来的人就是我
brave enough to try to escape.
你就是追捕者吗
Ah, you're The Catcher.
久仰大名
I've heard a lot about you.
人多吗
So, have there been many?
逃跑的可怜虫
Poor souls, I mean.
不多
No.
有水拦着逃不出去
The water does most of the work,
但时不时的
but every so often,
还是会有人犯傻
someone gets stupid
想试试
and gives it a go.
我不知道我不能出来
I didn't know I wasn't supposed to be outside.
怪我
My mistake.
你敢再犯
Make that mistake again,
就没有下次了
and it'll be your last.
我前几天看到报上报道了
I saw the papers the other day.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
警察工会主席到底是干什么的
So what does president of the policeman's union do, exactly?
依主席而定
Depends on the president.
明白了
I see.
阿尔弗雷德怎么样
How's Alfred?
比我想的爱发牢骚
W-Whinier than I thought.
不  他好多了
No, he-he's getting better.
那就好
Glad to hear it.
你们俩对捅他的人说谎了  是吧
You two lied about who stabbed him, didn't you?
你是为了这个来的
That's why you're here?
是吗
Is it?
是的
Yes.
你说谎了吗
Did you?
你骗我了吗
Lie to me?
没有
No.
我们要是没有犯人的描述
If we don't have a description of the culprit,
就找不到他
we won't find him.
我也希望能帮上你  警探
I wish I could help you, Detective.
阿尔弗雷德想自己对付他
Alfred wants to go after him on his own.
这就是你们骗我的原因
That's why you lied to me.
不是
No.
布鲁斯  看着我
Bruce, look at me.
不管阿尔弗雷德在盘算什么
Whatever Alfred is up to,
你都不要插手
you have to stay out of it.
这很危险
It's dangerous,
而且与你无关
and it's not your fight.
我把面包切太厚了  对吧
I cut this bread way too thick, didn't I?
布鲁斯
Bruce...
你说的我都懂
I understand what you're saying.
那就好
Okay, then.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon,
伦恩・摩尔
Len Moore.
警官  我有什么能帮你的
Officer, what can I help you with?
你声名远扬
You're a man with a reputation.
-是吗  -哥谭能真正破案的警探
- Oh, yeah? - A Gotham detective who actually closes cases.
尽力而为
I try.
我就是为这个来的
Uh, that's actually why I'm here.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是这样  几周前
See, a few weeks ago,
我接警了一起凶杀案
I was a first responder to a homicide.
死者名叫格蕾丝・费尔柴尔德
Victim's name was Grace Fairchild.
尸体在河边被发现  刺伤致死
They found her body down by the river, stabbed to death,
接手案子的警探
and the detectives who caught the case,
查不出结果  处理成了悬案
they got nowhere with it and moved on.
真遗憾  但这不可避免
I'm sorry to hear that, but it happens.
我希望你能继续侦办此案
I was wondering if you could pick up where they left off.
你想要我接手
You want me to take over the case?
是的
Yeah.
伦恩  我手上案子也一堆
Look, Len, I got a full boat here.
死者的家属
This victim's family,
该有人为他们伸张正义
they deserve justice.
-我理解  -她的凶手
- Well, yeah. - Her killer deserves
该为自己的所作所为付出代价
to pay for what he did.
这案子很残忍
This was a nasty one.
案子都很残忍
They're all nasty.
你有什么目的
What's your angle on this?
没有
No angle.
只是
It's just...
我们几个年轻的警员
Well, there's a few of us younger guys,
一直在关注你的事迹
and we've been watching what you've been doing
清理哥谭和哥谭市警局的乌烟瘴气
to clean up Gotham and the GCPD.
我也希望能和你并肩作战
And I want to be a part of it,
请你接手这个案子
and bringing you this case
就是我的方式
is my way of trying to do that.
我会看看的
I'll look into it.
法医鉴证室
准备好了吗
Ready to go?
准备好
Ready?
我一整天都在垂涎卢奇欧的意面
I have been dreaming about the carbonara at Luccio's all day.
新案子吗
New case?
算是吧
Uh, sort of.
一件凶杀悬案
It's an unsolved homicide
一个警员让我帮忙查查
a uni asked me to look into.
挺奇特的案子
It's an odd one.
是吗  怎么讲
Ooh, how so?
你不是早饿了吗
I thought you were hungry?
没办法
What can I say?
你说到凶杀案  我就不能自已了
You had me at homicide.
死者格蕾丝・费尔柴尔德两周前被发现
The victim, Grace Fairchild, was found two weeks ago.
四个月前就被报了失踪
She was reported missing four months earlier.
最后来自她的消息
Last anyone heard,
是她给母亲打的一通电话
she, uh, called her mother.
她说要在南格林威治的酒吧喝杯酒
Said she was having a drink at a bar in the South Village.
我就住那里啊
That's my neighborhood.
哪家酒吧
What bar?
警探排查了那一带
Detectives canvassed the area.
没人见过她
Nobody knows.
没线索  没消息
No leads, no tips.
也怪不得处理成悬案了
I'm staring to see why the case was dropped.
天哪  我们差不多大
God, we were almost the same age.
说不定能成为朋友的
We could've been friends.
南格林威治有几家地下酒吧
You know, they have a few speakeasies in the South Village.
这是新潮流
It's a new thing.
要从干洗店或者鞋店穿过去才能找到
You walk in through a dry cleaners or a shoe store to get inside.
不知道的话根本找不到
Easy to miss if you're not in the know.
谢谢  我会去查
Thanks, I'll check it out.
好
Good.
真高兴你打算调查此案
I'm glad you're looking into this.
不管凶手是谁
Whoever did this,
他就是个禽兽
he's a monster.
凯利
Kelly.
天哪
God.
情况不妙啊
Still bad.
你要干什么
What do you want?
我有个计划  但需要你的帮助
I have a plan, but I need your help.
什么计划
What plan?
我们要逃跑
We're going to escape.
我一定要离开这魔鬼岛
I'm getting off of this hell of an island,
不成功便成仁
or I'm gonna die trying.
哥谭
第一季  第十九集
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred?
你要去哪
Where are you going?
进城  布鲁斯少爷
Into the city, Master Bruce.
我了解雷吉
If I know Reggie,
他现在可能已经醉得半死了
he's probably drunk himself half to death by now
很快就会搞上劲儿更大的东西
and is moving swiftly on to the harder stuff.
他可能
I'll probably find him
蜷在哪个毒窝
holed up in a shooting gallery,
嗑得昏天暗地
totally off his maracas.
阿尔弗雷德  你不能去
Alfred, you can't go.
你身体还没好
You're not well.
没办法  布鲁斯少爷
No choice, Master Bruce.
他就会在这儿待几天
He'll only be here for a few days.
搞到毒品  就会走了
Enough time to get his fix, then he'll be off.
那咱们赶紧去吧
Well, then we better get going.
不要想着我会带上你  少爷
If you think I'm gonna take you, Master...
我的天
Oh, dear.
日安  莉迪娅
Good day, Lidia.
你有没有考虑我的建议
Have you thought about my offer?
跟你说过了  我这儿不卖
I told you already, my place is not for sale.
拜托  我求你了  再想想
Please, I beg of you, think again.
我只做个匿名合伙人
I will serve strictly as a silent partner.
由你继续打理日常经营
You will continue to run the day-to-day operations.
你是疯子吧  我说过了
Che pazzo, I told you already!
女士  拜托  我没有恶意
Madam, please, I-I meant no harm.
行了  女士
Okay, Mama.
明白了
You made your point.
女士  我向你保证
Madam, I assure you,
我对你这里真心感兴趣
I have a sincere interest in your establishment.
如果你不想要钱
If money is not what you seek,
你肯定也有什么想要的
surely there is something you want.
我孙女  安东尼娅
My granddaughter, Antonia,
她美貌非凡
she's beautiful,
品德高尚
virtuous,
天使一个
an angel.
她被一个巧舌如簧的吉他手
And she has been seduced
勾引了
by a silver-tongued guitar player.
那人就是魔鬼化身
Lucifer himself.
好悲惨啊
A tragedy.
你让她回家
You make her come home,
离开那个皮条客
leave this...pappone...
我就考虑你的提议
...then I'll consider your offer.
女士
Madam,
主日弥撒前她就能回来了
she will be home for Sunday Mass.
我跟你保证
You have my word.
这地方烂死了
This place is a dump.
根本不值钱
Real nickel-and-dime.
这里很有价值  盖布
It's worth far more than that, Gabe.
你只是还不懂
You just don't see it yet.
不行
No.
我又不是说正式接手这个案子
I'm not saying we officially take over the investigation,
就帮我查查
just help me look into it.
不行
No.
哈维
Harvey.
该为死者讨个公道
The victim deserves justice.
那还该为我讨个
Yeah, and I deserve
喜欢苍白的爱尔兰人和烹饪的哑巴超模呢
a mute supermodel who likes pasty Irish guys and loves to cook.
不行
It's not happening.
更何况  你我心里都清楚
Besides, we both know
公道才不是你想插手的真正原因呢
that justice isn't the real reason you want this one.
警探们
Hello, Detectives.
爱德  问你个问题
Ed, question:
你愿意多做些工作还是少做些工作
would you rather work more or less?
这是谜语吗
Is this a riddle?
你看吧
Exactly.
你帮定了  什么事
You're helping. What's up?
这是南格林威治有酒水经营许可证的
Uh, list of all establishments in the South Village
所有酒吧清单
with a current liquor license.
包括地下酒吧吗
Including speakeasies?
是的
Yes, siree--
其中有四家
four of which, you'll be pleased to know,
被之前的警探遗漏了
were missed by the original detectives.
非常好  爱德  谢谢
Ah, that's great, Ed. Thanks.
还有一件事
One more thing.
我之前看了一遍费尔柴尔德凶杀案的
I was going through the crime scene evidence
犯罪现场证据
from the Fairchild murder
有一件证物不见了
and, uh, there's a piece of evidence missing.
知道是什么吗
Any idea what it is?
不知道  但标签是"3A"
No, but it's labeled "3A."
你觉得你能找到吗
Think you can find it?
警探  我会解开这个谜题的
Detective, I will solve this puzzle.
你要来吗
You coming?
让我用西班牙语回答你
Let me say it in Spanish:
不要
No.
好吧  听着  你说得对
Okay, look, you're right.
我的确有野心
I'm ambitious.
我想让这里的人看到
I want to show people around here
情况会有所改变
that things are gonna change.
但是  哈维  没有你的帮助我做不到这一点
But, Harvey, I can't do that without your help.
我知道你现在洋洋自得
Look, I know you're riding high,
因为搞定了洛布什么的
what with getting over on Loeb and all.
但是有件事你得永远记住
But there's one thing you should always remember.
飞得离太阳太近
Fly too close to the sun,
你终会被灼伤
you're gonna get burned.
你说完了吗
You done?
-说完了  -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
那就起身跟我走
Then get your ass up.
就是这样
So that's it.
你是在告诉我
So you're trying to tell me
你真觉得我们可以逃出这里
you actually think we can get out of here.
我不就是这么说的吗
That's what I said, didn't I?
怎么逃
How?
用点花招和小伎俩
With cunning and guile.
但是没有你们帮助就成不了
But it won't work without your help.
为什么是我们
Well, why us?
为什么不叫你的朋友们
Why not your friends?
逃出去的过程中会发生什么事难以预料
There's no telling how this is all going to go down during the breakout.
万一事态不妙
Just in case it goes south,
我需要一些冷血无情的杀手在我身边
I need some stone cold killers by my side,
而不是一些可怜巴巴的受害者
not some whipped-ass victims.
有道理
That's fair.
计划是什么
What's the plan?
外面的岸边上有艘船
Outside, there's a boat down by the shore,
足以载我们六个逃离这个岛
big enough to carry the six of us off of this island.
一艘船
A boat?
你还有更好的主意吗
You have a better idea?
我前两天听见了直升机降落的声音
I heard a chopper land the other day.
轰隆隆的响炸天
Thumped like a son of a bitch.
我们为什么不飞出去
Why don't we fly out of here?
你们中有人会开直升机吗
Do any of you know how to fly a helicopter?
这就是原因了
That's why.
好吧
All right.
这艘船...
This boat...
你有钥匙吗
you got the keys to it?
没有
No.
还没拿到  但我会搞定的
Not yet, but I will.
所以你们加入  还是不加入
So are you in, or out?
三家无果  我走得脚都疼了
We're oh-for-three. My dogs are barking.
我通常不会抱怨去酒吧这种事
I'm hardly one to complain about going to a bar,
但这实在是太荒唐了
but this is getting ridiculous.
这的确枯燥  和其他案子一样
It's grunt work, just like any other case.
但这和其他案子并不一样
Except it's not just like any other case;
这是你的"业余爱好"
it's a hobby.
人人都得有点爱好
Everybody needs a hobby.
哥谭市警局  凶案组
GCPD homicide.
没错  她来过这里
Yeah, she was in here.
一段时间之前了
A while ago.
大概...三四个月之前
Maybe... three or four months?
你记得她
You remember her.
是的  她提过自己上的是我学校的对手院校
Yeah, she mentioned she went to a rival college of mine.
而且...
Plus...
而且什么
Plus what?
说实话  她的约会对象可性感了
To be honest with you, her date was hot.
约会对象
Her date?
记得他长什么样吗
Remember what he looked like?
只记得他很帅了
Just that he was good-looking.
而且衣冠楚楚
But classy, you know?
好吧
Okay.
该你了
Your turn.
为什么你这样一个成功  风趣
How is a successful, funny,
又比较帅的男人还是单身呢
mildly good-looking guy like you still single?
-比较  -也许不止"比较"  说嘛
- "Mildly"? - Maybe a little bit more than that. Come on.
你肯定有些问题
Something has to be wrong with you.
或许你说的对
Maybe you're right.
我曾经...
I've, uh...
我曾经有过很多段恋情
I've had plenty of relationships,
但最终  她们都...
but in the end, they...
不怎么合适
never seem to work out.
为什么呢
Why not?
我觉得是我追求的东西令人害怕
I think what I'm looking for frightens people.
好吧
Okay.
不  不是...
No, it's...
不是什么奇怪的事
It's nothing weird.
到底是什么
What, then?
听起来挺俗气的
It's gonna sound cheesy.
我不会笑的
I won't laugh.
我保证
I promise.
我想要寻找的...
What I'm looking for...
是无条件的爱
is unconditional love.
无条件的
Unconditional,
真实的  激情的爱
real, intense love.
很俗气  对吧
Cheesy, right?
相当的
Totally.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
还不错
It'll do.
厨房里有些酒
There's some wine in the kitchen.
你喜欢就开了吧
Open anything you like.
我来帮你拿外套
May I take your jacket?
这地方很有效吧
This place must work well.
什么意思
What do you mean?
对那些你带回来的女人
With the women that you bring back here.
其实我已经
Actually, it's...
有段时间
been a while
没带人来过了
since I've had anyone over.
我还真幸运
Lucky me.
我才幸运
I'm the lucky one.
谢谢你能给我机会
Thank you for taking a chance on me.
你逗我呢
Are you kidding me?
看看这地方
Look at this place.
我绝对能留下来...
I could definitely stay here...
过个夜
for a night.
如果他  回来了
Look, if he, uh, comes back in
或者你想起了其它什么
or you think of anything else,
给我打电话
give me a call.
没问题
Sure.
他来过这里  哈维
He was right here, Harvey.
是啊
Yeah.
你不会放手了吧
You're not dropping this one, are you?
不可能
Not a chance.
射击场
第八大道940号
梅布尔西大街52号
林肯街114号
波尔克射击场
梅布尔西大街52号
那么
So...
达成一致了吗
are we in agreement?
还没有
Not quite.
他说他还爱着那女孩
...says he still loves the girl.
不肯离开她
He won't leave her.
安东尼娅和我是天生一对
Antonia and I are destined to be together,
无论你做什么
and nothing you can do
都不会让我停止爱她
will make me stop loving her.
看到了吧
See what I mean?
真爱
True love.
要不要我给他一枪
You want me to put a slug in him,
看能不能让他松口
see if that loosens him up?
不用
No.
他是个吉他手
He's a guitar player.
断了手指
Lose the fingers.
你要我开枪打掉他的手指吗
You want me to shoot his fingers?
别用枪
Don't shoot them.
剪断
Lose them.
我正想见你呢
Just the man I wanted to see.
别这么说
Oh, don't say that.
吉姆好吃醋了
You're gonna make Jim jealous.
我刚完成费尔柴尔德的尸检
I finished the Fairchild autopsy
结果有些奇怪
and the results were a little strange.
怎么个奇怪法
Strange how?
格蕾丝・费尔柴尔德失踪了四个多月
Grace Fairchild was missing for over four months.
一般来说  这种绑架案
Usually, with these kind of abductions,
尸体上应该有多处外伤及虐待痕迹
there's a lot of trauma and abuse to the body,
但是她身上却没有
but not this time.
除了心脏和喉咙的几处刺伤外
Other than the stab wounds to her heart and her throat,
她身上几乎毫发无伤
her body was mostly pristine.
这说不通
That doesn't add up.
除非
Unless...
除非什么
Unless what?
你有没有想过她是自己跑掉的呢
You ever consider she ran off on her own?
就是说她的失踪和她的被杀毫无关联
That her going missing has nothing to do with her murder?
尸检结果与这相符
The findings would certainly support that.
也许吧
Maybe.
不
No.
不对  费尔柴尔德有一份很好的工作
No, Fairchild had a good job,
有房贷
a mortgage...
她失踪的那晚还给她母亲打了电话
Hell, she called her mother the night she went missing.
不  她没出走
No, she didn't run away.
她是被人抓走的
She was taken.
绑架她的人
And whoever took her
把她关了起来
kept her locked away
直到他完全准备好了
till he was good and ready...
才把她给杀了
and then he killed her.
我确定
I know it.
早上好
Morning.
睡得好吗
How'd you sleep?
睡得很香
Like a baby.
我想  吃完早餐
So I thought, after breakfast,
我们可以去看看派立克展览会
we could go to the, uh, Palick exhibit.
再过一星期就结束了
It's only in town another week.
我很想去  真的
I would love to, really,
但是我已经迟到了
but I am already late,
我要开早会  还有工作午餐
and I've got a morning meeting and a work lunch.
-重新安排嘛  -不行
- So reschedule it. - I can't.
昨晚和你一起真的很开心
I had a really good time with you last night.
希望还能再见到你
And I hope that I get to see you again.
那至少
At least, uh...
吃点早餐吧
have some breakfast.
我还得回家换身衣服  真的来不及了
Oh, I still have to go home and change and I am so late.
下次吧
Next time.
今晚给我打电话
Call me tonight.
如果你想的话  下班后
I can come over after work,
我可以过来
if you want.
杰森
Oh, Jason...
我真的要走了
please, I really have to go.
不
No.
你不能走
You don't.
穆尼女士
Miss Mooney.
真是意外啊
What a surprise.
有什么我能帮到你的吗
Is there something I can do for you?
这个嘛
Well...
给犯人们的物资
supplies were running low...
就快用完了
for the inmates.
物资在储藏室里
Those are in the storage room.
但是  当然了  你已经知道了
But then, of course, you already knew that.
我最不能容忍的
The one thing I won't tolerate...
就是说谎
is dishonesty.
你想逃走  是吧
You were trying to escape, weren't you?
不是
No.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
我会一枪打在你肚子上
I'm going to shoot you in the stomach.
起初你会感到压力感
You'll feel pressure at first.
跟着你就会有种前所未有的
Then you'll feel an intense burning
强烈烧灼感
like you've never felt in your life.
也许那会让你肯说实话
Maybe that will properly motivate you to be honest with me.
我再问你一次
I ask you again.
你是不是想逃走
Were you trying to escape?
不是
No.
真让人失望
How disappointing.
等等  不要
Wait, s-stop.
等等
Wait, wait.
我说谎了  但...
I was lying, but I...
但我不是想要逃跑
but I wasn't trying to escape.
你想杀了我吗
You were going to kill me?
割断我的喉咙
Slit my throat, perhaps?
我发誓  不是的
No, I swear.
不是要杀你
Not yours...
不是你
Not yours.
每晚入睡的时候  我都要向上帝祷告
Every night when I close my eyes, I pray to God
祈求噩梦不要降临
that nightmare doesn't come.
那个活生生的男人被拼接了
That... living, breathing man, stitched together with...
不同人的胳膊和腿
arms and legs that weren't his.
那是你创造的噩梦
That nightmare you created.
我见识过危险之人
I've faced dangerous men,
但没有一个如你一般可怕
but none like you,
人偶师
Dollmaker.
所以你宁愿自杀
So you'd rather take your own life
也不愿变成我的作品
than end up one of my creations?
是的
Yes.
穆尼女士
Well, Miss Mooney,
类似的事再发生
try anything like this again,
你的噩梦就会成真了
and your nightmare will come true.
如果有必要  即使你死了我也能让你活过来
I will bring you back from the dead, if I have to...
并把你打造成史无前例的作品
...and make you into something the world has never seen.
还有别的事吗
Was there something else?
没有了
No.
我可能会拿砖头砸烂你的脑袋呢
Could've smashed your head with a brick, you know?
你为什么要那么做
Why would you do that?
你为什么要说这种话
Why'd you even say that?
给你提个醒罢了  怎么了
Just thought you should know. What's up?
为什么要找我
Why're you looking for me?
刺伤阿尔弗雷德的那个人  雷吉・佩恩
Reggie Payne, the man who stabbed Alfred,
他还在哥谭
he's in Gotham.
你想让我帮你找他  好啊
And you need my help to find him. Okay.
阿尔弗雷德说他这几天肯定在射击场
Alfred said he'd be at a gun range for a few days,
但我已经查遍了城里的每个射击场
but I checked every one in the city.
毫无线索
Nothing.
谁会在射击场逗留啊
Who stays at a gun range for a few days?
说不通
Doesn't make any sense.
他就是这么说的
That's what he said.
他说雷吉会在"射击场[毒窝]"
Said Reggie'd be at a shooting gallery.
那不是射击场的意思  呆子
That's not the same as a gun range, silly.
你真该多出来走动走动了
You really need to get out more.
好了  好了
All right, all right, all right.
好好洗洗吧
Go get yourself cleaned up.
我马上过去
Back in a minute.
我们可以谈条件了吗
So shall we discuss terms?
是什么
So what is it?
首先要申明
Well, to be clear,
这并不是犯罪现场的证据
this isn't an actual piece of crime scene evidence.
据我看  证据早就没有了
It's long gone, as far as I can tell.
我找到的是一本登记薄里的复印件
What I was able to find is a photocopy,
藏得很深
buried deep in a logbook.
一颗破碎的心
It's a broken heart.
我觉得是手绘的
Hand-painted, I'd guess.
这是犯罪现场找到的吗
This was at the crime scene?
确定吗
You're sure?
不是这个啦
Well, not this, exactly.
复印件其实是副本...
You see, a photocopy is a replica...
行了  爱德  别闹了
Damn it, no, Ed, not now.
-怎么了  -我警告过你的
- What's wrong? - I warned you.
但你不听我的  现在我们都有麻烦了
But no, you had to go and get both of us burned.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你追查的这个男人
This guy you're after,
这不是他的处女作了
this is not his first rodeo.
他是个连环杀手
He's a serial killer.
看起来很美味
This looks delicious.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得我可能
I, uh... I think I may have
把羊排烤老了一点
overcooked the lamb... a little bit,
但...
but I-I, uh...
肯定没问题的
I'm sure it's fine.
你今天过得如何
How was your day?
挺好的  亲爱的
Wonderful, darling.
你呢
And how was yours?
挺好
Good.
谢谢关心
Thank you for asking.
我觉得你说对了
I think you might have been right...
是有点老了
about the lamb.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
没事的
It's fine.
在烤箱里时我还检查过两次呢
I checked it twice when it was in the oven,
我觉得温度可能是比显示的要高
and I think it might be hotter than it says it is...
知道吗
You know...
我觉得我们不合适
...I don't think this is working out.
不是因为你
It's not you.
是我的缘故
It's me.
我们本可以成为特别的一对儿
Could have had something special.
求你  别伤害我
Please. Please don't hurt me.
我还真以为  你是我的完美情人
You know, I really thought you were the one.
求你
Please.
不要啊
No, no.
别担心
Don't worry.
我迟早能找到她
Sooner or later, I'll find her.
我还是不懂
I still don't get it.
为什么费那么大事拿下这里
Why all that trouble for this pile of bricks?
这不是为了钱  盖布
This was never about money, Gabe.
不是为了钱
Not about money?
还能是为什么
What else is there?
人的动力有很多种
All kinds of things motivate people--
淫欲  野心  嫉妒
lust, ambition, envy.
好吧  你的动力是什么
Okay, what motivated you?
你为什么这么想要这里
Why do you want this place so bad?
很简单
It's simple.
我要在这里杀了马罗尼阁下
This is where I'm gonna kill Don Maroni.
到时候了
It's time.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
行动吧
Let's go.
门一打开  警报就会大作
Now, as soon as this door opens, an alarm will go off,
我们的时间可就不多了
and we will not have much time.
大门怎么办
What about the gate?
昨晚已经打开了
Unlocked last night.
拿上这个
Take these.
一到船上马上启动马达
Get the boat started as soon as you get there.
你不一起来吗
You're not coming with us?
我会来  我就回来  我得去接凯利
I'm coming, I'll be right back-- I need to get Kelly.
他路都走不动了  我们走吧
He can barely walk. Let's go.
算我重感情
Call me sentimental,
但我不能把他丢下
but I cannot leave him here.
你们最好别丢下我
And you better not leave me.
你骗了我  菲什
You lied to me, Fish.
我警告过你对我撒谎会有什么后果
I warned you what would happen if you lied to me.
我能用你的身体创造各种奇迹
Oh, what wonders I'm gonna make of your parts.
回见了  医生
See you around, Doc.
别管他了
Leave him there.
我们时间不多
We don't have much time.
走吧
Let's go.
这边
This way.
他们去劫船了
They're headed for the boat.
干什么呢  开大门啊
What are you doing, man? Open up the gate.
不行
I can't.
锁上了
It's locked.
什么
What?
菲什说她给解开了啊
Fish said she unlocked it.
-那婊子  -怎么了
- That bitch. - What?
菲什
Fish.
她给我们下了套
She set us up.
凯利  副驾
Kelly, other side!
你不是跟他们说你不会开飞机吗
You told them you couldn't fly, didn't you?
我撒谎了
I lied.
直升机
The chopper.
坐稳
Hold on!
菲什
Fish!
他绑架年轻漂亮的单身女人
He abducts young, single, attractive women
监禁她们  有时是一周
and he keeps them sometimes for a week,
有时几个月
sometimes for months.
然后他把她们的尸体丢在哥谭各个地方
Then he dumps their bodies around Gotham.
他杀了多少人
How many has he killed?
12个  或许更多
A dozen, maybe more.
每次他杀一个人
Every time he makes a kill,
都在犯罪现场留下个这个
he leaves one of these at the crime scene.
这是他的名片
It's his calling card.
那他是谁
So, who is he?
没人知道
No one knows.
理论是  他受过教育  相貌良好  有钱
Thinking is he's educated, decent-looking, rich.
但这只是个侧写
But that's just a profile.
有人称他为唐璜杀手
Some of the guys call him The Don Juan Killer.
更多人喊他食人魔
Most call him The Ogre.
那我怎么没听说过这人
So, why haven't I heard about this guy before?
公众也不知道
Why hasn't the public?
-这是哥谭市警局  -两位好
- It's the GCPD's... - Hey, fellas!
肮脏的小秘密
...dirty little secret.
只有少数高级警探知道这人的事
Only a handful of senior detectives know anything about this guy,
而且他们绝不会向媒体透露
and they sure as hell ain't leaking it to the press.
为什么
Why not?
因为食人魔会报复
Because The Ogre retaliates
调查他的警察
against any cop who investigates him.
他杀害他们所爱的人
He kills the people they love.
所以才没人抓住过这疯子  吉姆
That's why this lunatic hasn't been caught yet, Jim,
因为没人会蠢到去调查他
because no one's been stupid enough to investigate.
直到我出现
Until I came along.
所以我想问你  这案子你怎么发现的
Which makes me wonder how did you catch this?
我说了  一名警官拜托我调查的
I told you a fellow officer asked me to look into it.
谁啊
Who?
哪个警官
Which one?
小猫
Cat.
是他
That's him.
放松  老头子
Relax, old man.
我们不会打劫你
We're not gonna rob you.
你们来干什么
What are you doing here?
来跟你说话
Came to talk to you.
她是谁
Who's she?
别管
Never mind.
谁派你去我家的
Who sent you to my house?
谁派我
Who sent me?
回家吧  布鲁斯
Just go home... go on, Bruce.
否则你会惹上更多的麻烦
You'll be in more trouble than you are already.
那是我的药  给我
That's my medicine! Give me that!
我朋友问你问题呢
My friend just asked you a question.
我叫你给我
I said give me that.
否则呢
Or you'll what?
-别  -回答我
- Don't... - Answer the question!
我没想伤人
I didn't mean any harm.
我只是去拿文件的
I was just supposed to take some documents.
但阿尔弗雷德撞见我了
But Alfred walked in...
他没事吧
Is he all right?
Is he?
你捅伤了他
You stabbed him.
你在乎什么
What do you care?
我在乎
I care!
他还好吧
He's all right, isn't he?
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
丢出去
Throw them out!
-不要  -告诉我谁派你来的
- No! - Tell me who sent you!
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
你不该做这种事  布鲁斯
You shouldn't be doing this, Bruce.
只有阿尔弗能对付得了这些人
Only Alfie can deal with these people.
什么人
What people?
有个女人  玛希斯
There's a woman named Mathis
还有个叫邦德斯洛的男人
and a guy called Bunderslaw.
希德・邦德斯洛  是他跟我打的交道
Sid Bunderslaw-- he's the guy I dealt with.
但你得让阿尔弗处理这事
But you've got, you've got to let Alfie take care of this.
你不行  布鲁斯
Not you, Bruce.
这不是孩子能处理的事
It's not business for a child.
这个邦德斯洛
This man Bunderslaw...
他想要什么
what did he want?
只想知道你知道什么
Just to know what you knew.
看你的调查进展到什么地步了
To see how far your investigation had gone.
但他害怕了
But he was scared.
所以才派我去
And that's why he sent me.
能把包还我了吗
Now, can I have my bag back, please?
拜托
Please?
还给他
Give it back to him.
你
You.
你有病  佩恩先生
You're a sick man, Mr. Payne.
你需要帮助
You need help.
少教训我
Don't you patronize me.
我虽然有毛病
I may have vices, yeah,
但我是职业杀手
but I'm a professional.
你希望我去告诉邦德斯洛你发现他了吗
You want me to tell Bunderslaw that you're onto him?
因为他会来找你的
Because he'll come after you.
你根本没法阻止他
And there's nothing that you can do to stop him!
你就是个傻乎乎的小孩
You're just silly little children.
我会告密的
I'm gonna tell on you.
不  你休想
No, you won't!
不是我的主意
It wa... it wa... it wasn't my idea!
我发誓
I swear!
我得到命令骗你接下案子
I-I was ordered to get you to take the case.
谁命令你
Ordered by who?!
洛布
Loeb!
是洛布局长
It was Commissioner Loeb.
他叫我告诉你
He told me to tell you that...
我敬仰你
I looked up to you.
你激励了我
That you inspired me.
他叫我说
I mean, he-he told me to say
我想帮忙清理哥谭
that I wanted to help clean up Gotham.
和哥谭市警局
And, uh, the GCPD.
这桩案子
And that this case...
就是我的一份努力
this case was part of that.
他知道你无法拒绝
He knew you couldn't say no.
你像个好士兵那样听从了命令
And so you followed orders like a good soldier.
我没有选择
I-I didn't have a choice.
你知道洛布有什么本事
You know what Loeb can do.
非常清楚
All too well.
吉姆  听我说  你还没惹上麻烦
Jim, listen! You're still in the clear on this.
"没惹上"  他可能会去害小莱
"In the clear"? He could come after Lee!
如果他认为你在调查他的话
Only if he thinks you're investigating him.
想想啊
Think about it.
这案子你还没接
It's not on your docket.
也没有报道把你和案子联系起来
There's been no press linking you up to this case.
你不过就是问了些问题
Hell, all you've done is ask some questions
你现在放手就行
so you got to drop it now!
现在不是逞英雄的时候
This is no time to be a hero.
如果放手  我就放了一个连环杀手
If I drop it, I'm letting a serial killer go free.
他下个杀的人的血就在我手上
The blood of his next victim is on my hands!
如果你不放手  那就可能会是小莱的血
If you don't drop it, that blood could be Lee's.
这里是小莱
Hi, you've reached Lee.
请留言
Go ahead and leave a message.
小莱  尽快给我回电话
Lee, call me as soon as you can.
这很重要
It's very import...
你
You!
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
你说什么
Excuse me!
你给我下套
You set me up!
警探  我不知道你以为...
Detective, I don't know what you think...
别说话  听着
Don't talk. Listen.
滚开
Back off!
你敢...
Don't you...
我也想跟你妥协
I tried to work with you.
但你这下越界了
But now you crossed a line.
你敢冲我爱的人下手
You come after the one I love.
今后  我们按我的规矩来
From here on, we're playing my way.
不再玩游戏
No more games.
不再做交易
No more deals.
我要找到食人魔  把他关进监狱
I'm gonna find The Ogre and I'm gonna put him behind bars.
等我抓到他  我就会冲你来
And when I've done that, I'm coming after you.
我要抓到你  局长
I'm coming after you, commissioner.
你完了
You're done.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com